Contact

Via Pietro Casu, 16 Sassari, (SS) 07100 Italy

(+39) 333 3840979 (+39) 079 2859049

Languages

Persian (Mother tongue) Italian (Mother tongue) English (C1) French (A2) Spanish (A1)

Programming •

Java, JavaFX, Python, C, C++, Objective-C, .NET Framework, R, Latex, OpenCV, APEX, SQL, PL/SQL, MySQL, PHP, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, Django, XML, GWT, JSON, Shell Script.

Software

Vim, xCode, Android Studio, Windows Phone SDK, Matlab, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, Premiere Pro, VirtualBox, ISPConfig, Openstack, Puppet, OpenMediaVault, MongoDB, Metasploit, Wireshark, Git, Jira, Trac.

Hardware

Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Embedded Pi, Cubieboard, Torobot, TP-Link CPE210, CPE510, EAP225, Ubiquiti Nanostation M3 and Picostation.

Summary

I was born in Iran in 1993 and moved to Italy at the age of 7. I started studying programming languages at the age of 15 and began to work as a freelance programmer a couple of years later. At the age of 19 I was admitted to the University of Pisa as a Computer Engineering student. After finishing my bachelor I enrolled for a Master in Artificial Intelligence and Data Engineering. In the past years, beside studying for my examinations, I worked for IT Companies and for the Italian government, I took part in group projects and tried to startup my own ideas. During the academic year 2017/2018, my goals have shifted. I have developed a deep interest in Artificial Intelligence. Precisely, what really keeps me up at night is the complexity behind creating a mathematical model (to be translated into a computational architecture) capable of independent decision making and of generating original thoughts. To this very specific end, is the von Neumann architecture good enough or should a new one be conceived? Is it mainly a problem of programming? Finally, as said by Alan Turing in his seminal paper Computing Machinery and Intelligence, can machines think?

Education

2019 - 2020 Master of Engineering Studies - Artificial Intelligence University of Pisa, Italy
 2013 - 2019 Bachelor of Engineering Studies - Computer Engineering University of Pisa, Italy
 2008 - 2013 High School Diploma 100/100 - Scientific Lyceum Scientific Lyceum "G. Spano", Italy

Personal Studies

The following is a list of in-depth courses which I followed during my Bachelor of Engineering.

Complete Java Masterclass: Learn to master Java 8 core development.

Tim Buchalka

The Complete Networking Fundamentals Course: Start your journey to CCNA.

David Bombal
Keith Gebhardt

Understanding Modern Electronics.

Professor Richard Wolfson, Ph.D

Advanced C++ Programming: Intermediate to advanced C++, including C++ 11's additions.

Cisco Networking Fundamentals: Complete Cisco IT Networking Fundamentals course.

additions. John Purcell

Machine Learning: Hands-On Python & R In Data Science.

Kirill Eremenko, Hadelin de Ponteves

Introduction to Computer Vision I Master OpenCV 3 in Python.

Rajeev Ratan

Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach I.

Stuart J. Russell, Peter Norvig, F. Amigoni, S. Gaburri

Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach II.

Stuart J. Russell, Peter Norvig, F. Amigoni, S. Gaburri

Work Experience

2018 **ClassX S.r.l.**

Pontedera

Java Developer

I worked as Java developer for the ClassX S.r.I focusing to develop broadcasting software and hardware. I got a glimpse of what it means to work with Modern OpenGL, writing native drivers for custom broadcasting hardware as well as using JNI.

Operating Systems

Windows 7/8/10, Mac OS X, iOS, Android, Debian, Linux Mint, Arch Linux, Raspbian, OpenWRT, Kali Linux, Parrot OS, Tails.

Linkedin in

For full and detailed information regarding my work experience, projects and awards please refer to my Linkedin Profile: it.linkedin.com/in/rambodrahmani.

GitHub 🗘

"Sharing isn't immoralit's a moral imperative. Only those blinded by greed would refuse to let a friend make a copy."

GitHub Profile: github.com/rambodrahmani.

Academia.edu 🏛

For full and detailed information regarding my personal studies please refer to my **Academia.edu Profile**: pisa.academia.edu/

RambodRahmani.

2018 **ClassX S.r.l.**

Intership

I spent two months at ClassX S.r.I as part of my academic career as a Computer Science student at University of Pisa. I developed an Android Application used to receive SMS messages and forward them to the company software for broadcasting purposes.

2013 - 2016 System Administrator

Rambod Rahmani

Pontedera

I was involved in in-home Server Setup as part of our self-educating projects at EigenLab. Additionally I spent a great deal of time working on both dedicated servers and VPS (OS Installation, ISPConfig Setup and maintenance). The majority of my experiences as SysAdmin was focused on Linux Servers.

2014 - 2015 Boccaccio Club

Pisa, Italy

Software Programmer

Boccaccio Club iOS and Android App Development. Wireless Network Routing with Multiple Access Points: internet access is guaranteed only when the Boccaccio Club App is installed on your device. In order to achieve such an advanced authentication method I developed a custom captive portal named DYNAMO.

2015 PHOS Project

University of Pisa

Software Programmer

iOS and Android App development for PHOS Project (Aerospace project at University of Pisa part of the REXUS/BEXUS programme).

2013 Ciclope: Raspberry Pi based Humanoid

Rambod Rahmani, Giacomo Taormina

Software Development & Hardware Assembly

Ciclope is a Humanoid robot with the ability to see and analyse the external world using a camera. Its structure has up to 17 degrees of freedom.

It is a one-of-a-kind combination of Software and Hardware: it combines the latest OpenCV libraries and the RPi on board camera. I coded basic functionalities such as object-tracking and face-recognition, and its control interface using Python, C and C++.

2013 Ambulatory Proctology Office

Sardinia, Italy

Software Programmer

I developed a software named "Anamnesi" (Objective-C - MAC OS X) used to manage patients medical histories. Each patient is identified using his fiscal code and the ambulatory doctors are able to access all medical histories stored on a server wherever they are.

2012 **MALIBU Village**

Canet-Plage, Languedoc-Roussillon, France

Internship

I worked as IT Support at MALIBU Village as part of the "Leonardo Project" internship. This was the first time I had a hands-on experience with Ubiquiti Picostations.

2010 - 2012 Italian Navy

San Giorgio-class amphibious transport dock, Italy

Software Programmer

I coded a set of three software named **A.S.C** (**Acceptance, Sorting and Control**) for the Italian Navy. What started as a late night project to improve my coding skills ended up changing my life for ever when I was still a high school student. During more than two years of daily work I translated a NATO publication made in 2008 into machine language. Thanks to A.S.C. operators do not have to worry anymore about formatting and standardizing their messages: the software checks every line before sending the message and tells the operator how to correct any mistake.

3D Printing

- Geeetech Prusa i3 Pro B
- Anycubic I3 Mega
- Creality Ender 3 Pro
- Anycubic Photon

OpenWRT 🤝

As a member of EigenLab, a local hacklab in Pisa, I was involved in installing and configuring the OpenWRT Distribution on embedded devices that we used to build EigenNet: a local **Wireless Mesh Network**

Bitcoin B

in the city of Pisa.

I have been involved in Bitcoins as far as it regards Bitcoin Mining (CGMiner, CPUMiner, USB Miners), Mining Pools, Bitcoin Wallet and Full Bitcoin Node Configuration (Bitcoin Core).

Places 9

Iran, Italy, Germany, Spain, France, Belgium, Holland, Russia.

> Last updated: February 22, 2021

Awards, Scholarships and Certificates

2013 - 2016 **DSU Scholarship** DSU of Tuscany DSU Scholarship by DSU of Tuscany supporting my Bachelor of Engineering

Studies.

2013 - 2016 Italian Ministry of Education, University and Research Scholarship

Excellence Scholarship by MIUR supporting my Bachelor of Engineering

Studies.

2012 Intel Excellence in Computer Science Intel Corporation

Awarded to Rambod Rahmani for developing the A.S.C. Software.

2012 **National Excellence Registry** Italian Ministry of Education, University and Research

Awarded to Rambod Rahmani for developing the A.S.C. Software.

2012 **Certificate of Merit** Scientific Lyceum "G. Spano", Italy

Awarded to Rambod Rahmani for developing the A.S.C. Software.

2012 **Europass Mobility Nr. IT/00/2012/859/10**

Gymnasium Lyceum "D. A. Azuni" and ALFMED (Académie de Langues France

Méditerranée.).

A.S.C. Software 2011 Italian Navy - San Giorgio-class Amphibious Transport Dock

Software Development Certificate by the Italian Navy for developing the A.S.C.

Software.

Patents

2015 **DYNAMO** Ministry of Economic Development (Italy) - Request number: 102015000072776

> Captive portal software which allows for Wi-Fi Access Points to be configured so as to provide internet access only to those devices where a required iOS/Android App is installed. Otherwise the device only has internet access as far as it is needed to install the required App. I developed this custom Captive Portal in order to achieve the advanced authentication method required by Boccaccio Club and thanks to their financial support I was able to patent DYNAMO.

Events

May 2015 **International World Wide Web Conference 2015** Florence, Italy

Research, development, and applications of the topics related to the Web.

May 2015 **HEUREKA 2015** Berlin, Germany

One of the main founders conferences in the German--speaking world.

May 2015 **Berlin Talent Summit 2015** Berlin, Germany

Europe's leading recruiting conference for high-potentials.

9th EXPO-SCIENCES EUROPE 2012 (ESE) July 2012 Tula, Russia

9th MILSET Expo-Sciences Europe (ESE 2012) held in Tula, Russia.

April 2012 I Giovani E Le Scienze 2012 Federation of Scientific and Technical Associations

The A.S.C. Software was selected as one of the best 30 in the whole country.

nterests

Professional: Startup, Computer Science, Geolocation Systems, Hardware, Smartphones, iOS, Android, Embedded systems, Web development, App development, Software design, Networking, Linux, Hacking, Penetration Testing, Computational Complexity, Artificial Intelligence, Artificial Neural Networks, Computer Vision.

Personal: Running, Chess, Cosmology, Astronomical observations, Quantum Computer Science, Physics and Math.